# DECLAN MCKELVEY-HEMBREE

# Software Engineer

#### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Science. Computer Science

Washington University in St. Louis

**m** 08/2012 - 12/2015

# **SKILLS**

# Web Development

CSS **Firebase** HTML **MODX** MySQL **lavascript** Node.js PHP Vue Wordpress

#### Application Development

AR	Arduino	C#	
Electrical Engineering			Electron
Java	Unity	VR_	
Support Disciplines			

Blender **Excel** Gitlab lira Photoshop

# Soft Skills

Adaptability Collaboration Creativity Organization **Problem Solving** Time Management

#### SUMMARY

Declan McKelvey-Hembree is a seasoned software developer with 8 years of agency experience creating websites, applications, and games for major brands. He's a versatile problem-solver with broad cross-disciplinary knowledge who frequently learns new technologies and skills on a per-project basis. He's always looking for opportunities to collaborate on unique projects and diversify the capabilities of software teams.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Application Developer

#### 160over90

苗 03/2022 - Present

- Shipped 30+ university websites to clients like the University of San Diego and Princeton, increasing annual giving and undergraduate applications. Yale's campaign site, For Humanity, helped Yale reach \$1.18B in annual donations.
- Developed and maintained a customer acquisition platform for T-Mobile serving 700K+ customers and 500+ T-Mobile employee users.
- Created several educational video games and provided on-the-ground support for USAA's Fort Innovate, a science museum exhibition about military inventions that toured to 10 cities nationwide.

### Application Developer II

#### 1600ver90

**=** 10/2019 - 03/2022

- · Architected and developed a virtual Masterclass platform for Sephora, where ticketed users could sign up for exclusive how-to livestreams from fashion influencers and then have oneon-one conversations with them in breakout rooms.
- Developed a variety of fan activities for Blizzard Entertainment's annual fan convention, Blizzcon, including fan art poster design software and printing stations, and MVP voting software that was used 70K+ times over the course of one weekend.
- Created a reusable suite of video games and interactive experiences for the annual Army/Navy promotional football game, including a pixel art infinite runner, a Kinect football game, a Hall of Fame interactive experience, and a digital recreation of the 1962 match based on archival materials.

# Application Developer II

#### **Fusion Marketing**

**=** 03/2017 - 10/2019

- Developed and provided on-site support for 20+ experiential activations, including creating the "Bud Light Victory Fridges", IoT devices placed in Cleveland bars which contained free Bud Light, but were locked until the Cleveland Browns won a game. This marketing stunt created 2.6B earned media impressions, 313M social impressions, and a sales increase of 500K bottles.
- Gamified customer lead intake for HSBC by creating a "Golf Swing Art" application, which used motion tracking and real time 3D rendering to turn customer's golf swings into unique, shareable works of art.
- Created a parody genetic testing site, "23 and Me", to promote the launch of South Park's 23rd season. Users could take a personality quiz and receive their "genetic matches" from among 128 characters on the show. This led to 700K+ users signing up for additional marketing from Comedy Central.

# Application Developer

# **Fusion Marketing**

**#** 06/2016 - 03/2017

- Developed a number of sites for Anheuser-Busch brands, including Goose Island, Elysian, and Michelob Ultra. Unified CMS systems across brands for easier cross-training and management, and built one-off custom pages for special events.
- Ideated and executed the Marriott Art of Innovation, an interactive installation with 4 unique generative art experiences based on the user's heart rate, movement, and pose. This exhibit toured internationally to celebrate the launch of various new Marriott properties.
- Created the Tailgate Club platform, an integrated e-commerce experience allowing for à la carte customization and purchase of tailgate packages. Built and managed a complex inventory system allowing for bundling, discounts, and add-ons, and a daily manifest generation system for on-site fulfillment.